如果你有足够的时间和胆量
If you've got the time and the stomach for it,
我这儿有个故事要讲给你听
I've got a story for you.
关于魔法与女巫的传说
A tale of magic and witches,
关于冒险与怪物的奇谭
of quests and of monsters.
关于善与恶的较量
Of good and of evil.
但别搞错了
But make no mistake.
这可不是什么童话故事
This is no fairy tale.
也不会有幸福美满的结局
And there are no happy endings.
你熟悉的那个世界早已消亡
The world you know is gone,
在远古大战的烈焰中灰飞烟灭
consumed by the flames of a great war long ago
当死亡如雨点般从天而降时
when death rained from the sky.
如今只剩下这片"失落之地"
All that's left now are the Lost Lands,
盘踞着在阴影中扭曲蠕动的怪物
filled with twisted creatures that dwell in the shadows.
残存的人类龟缩在最后一座城市里
What remains of humanity takes refuge in a single city.
很久以前 有位神秘女巫
Long ago, a mysterious witch,
灰艾丽斯 从失落之地现身
Gray Alys, emerged from the Lost Lands.
这就是我们相遇的故事
This is the story of how we met
也是她拯救我们两人的传奇
and how she saved the both of us.
停下你们手里的活!
Stop your work!
都给我停下!
这就是违抗教会的下场
Let this be an example to all.
看谁还敢忤逆圣教
No one shall defy the church.
人们都说只要找灰艾丽斯
They say you can buy anything
任何愿望都能用钱买到
you might desire from Gray Alys.
但最好别这么做
But it's better not to.
可人们还是前仆后继找你帮忙
And still the people seek your help.
他们愚昧无知
They're ignorant, uneducated.
有穷有富 但都走投无路
Some are poor, some rich. All are desperate.
我从不拒绝任何人
I refuse no one.
知道教会怎么评价你这种人吗?
Do you know what the church says about the likes of you?
你肯定要开始说教了
I'm sure you're going to tell me.
说你是恶魔的使徒
That you are of the devil
铲除你是我们的神圣职责
and it's our duty to root you out.
以山底城统治者
In the name of the Overlord,
圣教大祭司
ruler of the City Under The Mountain,
至高领主之名
High Priest of the Faith,
我宣判你 灰艾丽斯
I sentence you, Gray Alys,
处以绞刑
to death by hanging.
忏悔吧 魔女
Repent, woman.
我这是怎么了?
What is happening to me?
你已经被蛊惑了
You cannot be trusted.
成了女巫的奴隶
You're a slave to the witch.
给我追杀她
Hunt her down.
- 集合 - 遵命大人
- To me. - Yes, ma'am.
现身吧 魔女
Show yourself, witch.
动手啊
Do it.
快动手
妖女!
Witch!
我会找到你的
I will find you.
你将在炼狱中焚烧
You will burn in hell.
女巫！你他妈就该下地狱被烧成灰！
You will burn in hell, witch!
那个绞不死的女巫
The witch that will not hang.
如果一个人想伏击另一个人
If a man wanted to ambush another man,
这里就是绝佳地点
this would be the perfect spot.
趁他眼睛还没适应黑暗就扑上去
Jump him while his eyes were still adjusting to the dark.
最好再带三四个帮手
Maybe even bring three, four friends.
确保万无一失
Make sure the job got done right.
这玩意儿从来就没好使过
This thing has never worked.
但这个永远不会失手
But this never fails.
灰艾丽斯
Gray Alys.
听出我的脚步声了?
Did you recognize my footsteps?
不 是你的善意
No. Your kindness.
这座城市越来越堕落
This city gets worse and worse,
但你始终如此慷慨
but you have always been so generous
从我小时候就是
ever since I was a child.
只对你如此
Only to you.
你从不向我索取任何东西
You never ask anything of me.
真奇怪
Strange.
你的声音和我年轻时听到的一模一样
You sound no different to when I was young,
但你现在应该和我一样老了吧
but you must be old now like me.
更老
Older.
老得多
Much older.
-我是杰雷斯 -守望团团长
- I'm Jerais. - Captain of the Overwatch.
是领主派你来的?
Have you come on behalf of the Overlord?
还是他的王后?
Or perhaps his queen?
什么风把您吹来见我这等人?
What brings you to visit one like me?
据说只要付出代价 你就能实现愿望
It is said that for a price, you grant wishes.
你想买什么?
What do you wish to buy?
退下
Leave us.
我觉得这不妥
I'm not sure if that is wise.
有人说你来自失落之地
Some say you came from the Lost Lands
知晓那里栖息的生物
and that you know the things that live there.
黑暗的 非自然的异类
Dark, unnatural things.
这就是你想从我这里得到的?
Is this what you want from me?
听童话故事?
To tell you fairy tales?
我想要获得化身野兽的力量 灰艾丽斯
I want from you the power to become a beast, Gray Alys.
超越凡人之躯 吓到你了?
To be more than human. Does that shock you?
我见识太多 早就不容易被吓到了
I have seen too much to be shocked so easily.
所以你能卖给我变形术的秘诀?
So you can sell me the secret of shapeshifting?
变成狼?
To a wolf?
你确定想要所求之物?
Are you certain you want what you ask for?
你得到的东西可能会让你后悔
You might not be happy with what you receive.
- 这不关你的事.- 我不得不帮忙.
- This is not your concern. - I am compelled to help.
- 但我警告所有来找我的人.- 我不是"所有人"
- But I warn all who come to me. - I'm not all.
- 嗯.- 你会接受我的提议吗?
- Mm. - Will you accept my offer?
我从不拒绝任何人.我会雇个猎手
I refuse no one. I'll hire a hunter.
我们会找到变形者夺取它的力量
We'll find you a shapeshifter and take its power.
给我到月圆之夜的时间
Give me until the full moon
就能给你想要的东西
and I will bring you what you desire.
你要去哪?
Where will you go?
失落之地
To the Lost Lands.
怎么了杰瑞斯?
What is it, Jerais?
你真的来者不拒?
Do you refuse no one?
来者不拒
No one.
那就收下这个当报酬.我要为自己买愿望
Then accept it as my payment. I wish to buy for myself.
这时计在我家族传承了数代
This timepiece has been in my family for generations.
是我最珍贵的宝物
It's my most valuable possession.
你想要什么愿望?
And what do you wish for?
我要你让她失败
I want you to fail her.
守望者立誓效忠
The Overwatch is sworn to loyalty,
你却背叛女王
yet you betray your queen.
我很忠诚
I am loyal.
我比她更清楚什么对她有益
I know what's good for her better than she knows herself.
她追求的力量会毁了她
This power that she seeks will destroy her.
我只是想帮忙
I only want to help.
你说谎杰瑞斯
You lie, Jerais.
你酸味都快溢出来了
You reek of jealousy.
我不和你争辩
I will not argue with you.
若不愿与我交易我就离开
If you will not sell to me, I will leave.
我从不拒绝任何人
I refuse no one.
你会得到想要的
You shall have what you want.
呃啊!
Argh!
对不起
I'm sorry.
你想要什么?
What is it you want?
救救我
Help me.
该死
Shit.
你又尿裤子了?
Did you wet yourself again?
不能用铃铛吗
Can't you use the bell,
老不死的蠢货?
you old disgusting fool?
伟大的霸主啊
The mighty Overlord.
难以相信这些都是你建造的
Hard to believe you built all this.
他们居然还畏惧你
And that they still fear you.
你不过是个肮脏的猪猡
You're nothing more than a filthy pig,
和所有男人一样
just like all men.
我的女王?
My queen?
所有男人,除了一个
All men, except for one.
先别走
Don't leave yet.
我必须走了
I have to.
趁他们没发现我
Before they see me.
不能留在这里
I can't stay here.
快点回来.求你了
Hurry back. Please.
我会的
I will.
也许吧
Perhaps.
站住！霸主麾下办事！
Halt, in the name of the Overlord.
你在这鬼鬼祟祟干什么?
What are you doing here?
酒越烈
The stronger the spirits,
人越菜
the weaker the senses.
跟我们走一趟
You're coming with us.
别动!
Stop!
这瓶还剩半壶呢
That was half full.
听说你是荒野猎人 常年在失落之地游荡
I hear you're a hunter, that you travel the Lost Lands.
我需要这种人才
I have use of such a man.
老子是来打牌的 不是来唠嗑的
Came here to play cards, not to talk.
全押
All in.
现在愿意开口了?
You ready to talk now?
报上名来
What's your name?
博伊斯
Boyce.
我要找个向导
I'm looking for a guide.
熟悉失落之地的那种
Someone who knows the Lost Lands.
- 我出场费很贵 - 老子有的是钱
- I'm expensive. - I have money.
看得出来 毕竟你兜里大半都是我的钱
I know you do. Most of it's mine.
你配得上这个价吗?
Are you worth it?
我要是不配 你还会坐在这跟我扯淡?
Would you be here talking to me if I wasn't?
失落之地可不是城里人该去的地方
The Lost Lands are no place for city folk.
怎么说?
Why is that?
因为城里人都是弱鸡
Because they're weak.
你看我像弱鸡吗?
Do I look weak to you?
听着
Look.
出了这道城墙 什么王法
Outside these walls, the laws of the city,
人伦 甚至自然法则 统统不作数
of man, even of nature, they don't apply.
所以不管你在城里多牛逼
So whoever you think you are here,
到了荒野就是个拖油瓶
out there you'd just be a hindrance.
不如打个赌
Let's make a deal.
要是我拖你后腿
If I ever slow you down,
你随时可以把我当累赘扔掉
you have my permission to leave me behind.
反之亦然
And I'll do the same to you.
为啥非要出城?
Why do you want to leave the city?
我要找一个能变身野兽的男人
I'm looking for a man who can turn into a beast.
男人都是禽兽
All men are beasts.
但并非都是怪物
But not all men are monsters.
你在找变形者
You're looking for a shapeshifter.
对 必须在他老巢宰了他才能夺取力量
Yes. I need to kill it in its lair to take its power.
我倒是听过这号人物
I've heard of such a man.
你知道什么情报?
What do you know of him?
人称巨狼萨尔多
They call him Sardor, the Great Wolf.
这个萨尔多住在哪?
Where does this man, this Sardor, live?
骷髅河地界
In a place called Skull River.
骷髅河...
Skull River.
正是我要去的地方
That's my destination.
那地方没几个人去过
Not many have travelled there.
- 也没人活着回来 - 带路...
- No one's come back. - Guide me...
这玩意儿归你了
and this can be yours.
听说过这玩意 头回见实物
I've heard of these. Never seen one.
我要了
I'll take it.
还有你偷我的那枚金币
And the coin you stole from me.
等我到了骷髅河自会结账
You'll receive your payment once I get to Skull River.
你朋友?
Friends of yours?
我这人没啥朋友
Yeah, I don't have many friends.
彼此彼此
Me neither.
抄家伙!
Gun!
啊!
Argh!
给我搜
Find them.
那贱人弄死了我的蛇!
That bitch killed my snake!
无人可违逆教会
No one shall defy the Church.
是教会用律法守护着
It is the Church that protects the peace
这座城市的安宁
of this city with its laws.
是教会让无信者心怀敬畏
The Church that puts fear into the hearts of the godless.
是教会将迷失之地的
The Church that keeps the evils
邪恶阻挡在外
of the Lost Lands at bay.
我等乃神的使者
We are God's instruments,
降世护佑尔等免受邪祟侵扰
placed on this earth to protect you from such evils.
追捕罪人、异端与女巫
Hunt down the sinners, the heretics, and the witches.
押来见我者必有重赏
Bring them to me and you shall be rewarded.
灰艾丽斯带着个男人
Gray Alys, with a man.
两人一同出城了
They left the city together.
民众已不再敬畏我们
The people lose respect for us.
"绞不死的女巫"
"The witch that will not hang."
灰艾丽斯成了他们反抗的象征
Gray Alys has become a symbol of their defiance.
她留你在十字架上苟活是在羞辱教会
She left you alive on that cross to humiliate us.
这女人必须死
This woman needs to die.
还有件事
There is another matter.
- 这是? - 你来说
- What is this? - Tell him.
快说
Tell him.
有对男女去找过她
A man and a woman went to see her.
我听见名字了
I heard their names.
是杰瑞斯和女王
It was Jerais and the queen.
若女王与异端勾结
If the queen has been consorting with a heretic,
那就是自寻死路
it would be her downfall.
确保女巫上绞架前
Make sure the witch makes a full confession
招供彻底
before she hangs.
不许出错
No mistakes.
不妙
No good.
头回见男人为条蛇动感情
Never saw a man get emotional about a snake before.
谁动感情了 只是...
I'm not emotional, it just--
那可是条极品好蛇 真的
It was a damn good snake, that's all.
给 撞针掰直了 现在应该好使
Here. The pin was bent. It should work well now.
只要你别再拿它砸人脑袋
As long as you stop beating men to death with it.
聪明人可能会选择半路干掉雇主
A clever man might choose to kill his client on the road
提前拿钱跑路
and take his payment early.
可惜没人说过我聪明
But no one ever accused me of being a clever man.
罗斯的据点到了
This is Ross's place.
他和妹妹玛拉都是我的老相识
He and his sister Mara are old friends of mine.
是吗?
Are we?
罗斯
Hey, Ross.
见到你真好
It's good to see you.
还有玛拉
And Mara.
- 还是这么热情 - 好久不见
- Welcoming as ever. - It's been a while.
你养尊处优了
You look soft.
看来城里日子过得滋润
The City has been treating you well.
- 女人也没少睡吧 - 嗯
- As have the women, I bet. - Mm.
哦吼!
Ooh-ooh!
这位是我的旅伴灰雅莉丝
Uh, meet my traveling companion, Gray Alys.
欢迎
Welcome.
博伊斯的友人就是我们的朋友
A friend of Boyce is a friend of ours.
我要从萨铎那里获得的力量
Gray Alys: The powers I want from Sardor
在他的巢穴里最为强大
will be strongest in his lair.
到骷髅河还要多久?
How much longer till Skull River?
- 一周 或许更久 - 我需要他保持狼形
- A week, maybe longer. - I need him as a wolf.
所以得赶在月圆前抵达
So we need to get there before the full moon.
这可不简单
That won't be easy.
要是简单还用得着你？
Well, if it was easy, I wouldn't need you.
唯一的捷径是沿着铁轨走
The only way would be following the train tracks.
隧道能穿山而过
The tunnels cut through the mountains.
虽然危险 但能省一两天
It'd be dangerous, but we'd save maybe a day or two.
没错
Yeah.
你该再来一杯
You need another drink.
每次见我都这么开心
Always happy to see me.
这破地方太无聊了
It gets boring out here.
她可真走运
Lucky her.
所以那个跟你同行的女人
So, who is this woman
什么来头?
you're traveling with?
少打听
None of your concern.
你喜欢她?
Do you like her?
不像对你这样的喜欢
Not the way I like you.
啊
Ah.
又要等一年才能见到你?
Will it be another year until I see you again?
嗯 如果我还能活着
Mm. If I'm still alive.
在失落之地 一年足够沧海桑田
One year--a long time in the Lost Lands.
人来人往
You come, you go.
我对你一无所知
I don't know anything about you.
你想知道什么?
What do you want to know?
你也会感到孤独吗?
Do you ever get lonely?
会
I do.
让我告诉你什么是孤独
Let me tell you about loneliness.
想象有个孩子...
Think of a child...
置身黑暗
out there in the darkness.
惊恐万状
Afraid.
父母被人活活打死...
His parents beaten to death...
就在他眼前
right in front of his eyes.
男孩在荒原流浪
The boy travels the wasteland,
躲避着亡命之徒
hiding from the outlaws
白天躲避掠夺者,
and the raiders during the day,
夜晚对抗怪物和食尸鬼.
and the creatures and the ghouls at night.
直到某天那个男孩长大成人,
Till one day that boy becomes a man,
心肠和头脑都变得冷硬.
and his heart and his mind harden.
但他仍继续孤独前行,
But still he travels on, silently,
害怕与人亲近唯恐失去.
scared to get close to anyone for fear of losing them.
这就是孤独.
That is loneliness.
那个小男孩就是你.
And that little boy was you.
不.放屁,当然不是.
No. Hell, no. Of course not.
我这辈子从没掉过一滴泪.
I've never cried a day in my life.
你根本一点都不了解我.
You really don t know anything about me.
这些是我们最后见到的友善面孔.
Those are the last friendly faces we'll see.
现在前方只剩下失落之地了.
There's only the Lost Lands ahead of us now.
你在这里做什么?
What are you doing here?
祈祷霸主早日归来.
Offering a prayer for the Overlord's swift return.
大主教,您的专列和大批
Patriarch, the train and a large contingent
执法者已经离城.
of your enforcers have left the city.
-谁批准的?-我.
- Who authorized this? - I did.
-他们去哪?-追捕女巫灰艾丽斯.
- Where are they going? - To catch the witch Gray Alys.
-她涉嫌异端罪.-你的人应该留守.
- She is wanted for heresy. - Your men are needed here.
街上骚乱愈演愈烈.
There is growing unrest in the streets.
您让我们陷入危险了,大主教.
You leave us vulnerable, Patriarch.
巫术罪当处死,
Witchcraft is punishable by death,
女巫及其同党皆不可赦.
both for the witch and all who consort with her.
我不在乎她或她的所作所为.
I do not care about her or what she does.
-为何如此?-休得质问.
- And why is that? - Do not question me.
-我代表霸主发言.-恕我冒犯.
- I speak for the Overlord. - Forgive me.
但您说得对,时局动荡.
But you are right, these are dangerous times.
霸主的掌控日渐衰弱.
The Overlord's hand is losing its grip.
我到处看到违抗之举.
I see defiance everywhere.
-还有流言.-什么流言?
- And there are rumors. - What rumors?
-我不能.-什么流言?
- I cannot. - What rumors?
关于您的不忠.
Of your infidelity.
纯属谎言.
Nothing but lies.
没错.卑劣之徒的恶毒谗言.
Yes. Vile words spoken by the basest of tongues.
但即便在渣滓中,谎言也有力量.
But even amongst the scum and rabble, lies have power.
王后犯有勾结女巫之罪.
The queen is guilty of consorting with a witch.
我现在看清楚了.
I see it clearly now.
把灰艾丽斯和她的供词带来.
Bring me Gray Alys and her confession.
余下由我处理.
I will do the rest.
霸主命不久矣,
The Overlord is dying,
没有子嗣,王后势单力薄.
and with no heir, the queen is weak.
很快都城将迎来新纪元.
Soon, there will be a new day in the city.
伴随新黎明到来的,会是新霸主.
And with the new dawn, a new Overlord.
啊!求求你!
Aah! Please!
-天啊.-不!
- God. - No!
我知道的都说了!
I told you all I know!
啊!我发誓!
Aah! I swear!
不!不!不!
No! No! No!
住手!不要!
Stop! No!
骷髅河!
Skull River!
他们就在那儿
That's where they're going.
骷髅河!
Skull River!
他们就在那儿
That's where they're going.
烧了它
Burn it.
博伊斯 你在这有家人吗?
Do you have a family out here, Boyce?
有家吗?
A home?
遗忘之地是个孤独的地方
The Lost Lands are a lonely place.
城里也一样
The city, too.
他们叫它裂隙城
They call it the Rift.
前面有个安全渡河点
There's a place up ahead where we can make a safe crossing.
赛勒斯!
Sirus!
老头你在哪?
Where you at, old man?
那是我朋友的缆车
That's my friend's cable car.
老赛勒斯收一枚银币就载人过河
Old Sirus will take us over for a silver coin.
对岸有他养的新马
He keeps fresh horses on the other side.
你付钱
You're paying.
赛勒斯?
Sirus?
在这等着
Wait here.
博伊斯?
Boyce?
看来赛勒斯有访客了
Seems Sirus had visitors.
我们也是
So do we.
所以你就是博伊斯 那个猎魔人
So you're Boyce. The Hunter.
我们问老头你是不是已经过河了
We asked the old man if you had already crossed.
他嘴挺严
He wasn't very helpful.
我一直挺喜欢赛勒斯
I always liked Sirus.
你身边是谁啊 猎魔人?
Who is that with you, hunter?
收起你的巫术把戏 妖女
None of your tricks, witch.
你都不敢直视我们
You can't look us in the eye.
交出她 饶你不死
Hand her over and we'll let you live.
她脑袋可值钱
There's a bounty on her head.
抱歉 她先雇的我
Sorry, she hired me first.
没想到你个老江湖还挺讲道义?
A man of principle. Who'd have thought?
交人 或者一起死
Give us the witch or you both die.
不交
No.
与圣教会为敌者
No one shall defy the Church.
你们自称神的仆人?!这算哪门子神?!
You say you're servants of God?! What kind of God is this?!
复仇之神
The vengeful kind.
你们来找怪物
You came here looking for a monster.
现在找到了
Now you found one.
博伊斯...
Boyce...
看好了
Behold.
见证奇迹吧
A resurrection.
不!
No!
博伊斯快走
Boyce, we have to go.
- 呃!- 走!
- Argh! - Let's go!
快!
Quick!
啊!
Argh!
呃!
Ah!
切断缆绳！
Cut the cable.
快砍断缆绳!
Cut the cable!
快砍啊!
Cut it!
呃啊!
Argh!
得往上爬!
We have to climb!
动作快!
Come on!
啊!
Argh!
她为什么没杀我?
Why didn't she finish me?
她尽力了
She tried.
确实是个女巫
A witch, indeed.
怎么过去?
How do we cross?
得绕路走
We have to go around.
那就动身吧
Then let's move.
他们会往山脉方向逃
They'll be headed for the mountains.
不,他们正走向地狱
No. Hell is where they're headed.
你还好吗?
You all right?
醉得厉害
Drunk.
哼!
Hmm!
多谢
Thank you.
刚才差点就死了
I could've died back there.
不,你死不了
No, you couldn't.
在送我到骷髅河之前都不会
Not until you get me to Skull River.
好了 我准备好了
Okay. I'm ready.
能帮我缝下伤口吗?
Would you mind stitching me up?
当然
Of course.
我想我现在可以安心昏过去了
I think I'd like to pass out now.
缝得不错
Nice work.
还是疼
Still hurts.
喝了这个
Drink this.
在想你朋友的事?
You're thinking about your friends?
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
罗斯是个好人
Ross was a good man.
我们相识多年
Known him a long time.
玛拉
Mara.
我要让他们血债血偿
I'm going to kill them for what they did.
你为什么来荒野游荡,博伊斯?
Why do you travel out here, Boyce?
我爱城市的烟火气
I love the city, the people.
烈酒,美食
A strong drink, good food.
但只有在这里才感到完整
Yet a part of me only feels at home here.
听风的声音
Listening to the wind.
看影子的舞蹈
Watching the shadows.
看到没,灰艾丽斯?
See there, Gray Alys?
注意到光芒如何流转了吗?
See the way the lights shimmer and shift?
盯着看久了能看出形状
You can see shapes in them if you look long enough.
确实
Yes.
真美
It's beautiful.
就知道你能看懂
I knew you'd see.
我们骨子里是一类人
We're alike, you and I.
血脉相连
In our blood.
天生就该同行
We're two of a kind.
你眼神早就出卖了你
I could see it in your eyes.
你怀上了
You are pregnant.
滚吧
You may go now.
耳朵聋了吗?
Did you hear?
你当然聋着
Of course you didn't.
有继承人了
We have an heir.
虽然这事跟你没半毛钱关系
Not that you had anything to do with it.
想知道新领主的爹是谁吗？
Do you want to know who the father
of the new Overlord is?
博伊斯
Boyce.
就这名字
That's his name.
区区猎户
A simple hunter.
老娘当年也是个傻白甜
I once was a simple girl myself.
现在呢？
Look at me now.
火车要来了
The train.
只能走山路,不然会被追上
We'll need to take the pass or they'll run us down.
玩命的路
It'll be dangerous.
入夜后山里有恶魔游荡
When night falls, demons roam these mountains.
没得选
We have no choice.
就在这儿刚正面
This is where we make a stand.
搭把手
Help me with these.
篝火得烧整宿
We need a fire all night.
只有火能镇住它们
Flame is the only thing they fear.
时间不多了
We don't have long.
准备迎战
Prepare yourself.
来了来了
Here they come.
灰艾丽斯
Gray Alys.
你就不该
You should not have
回这鬼地方
come back here.
撒手
Leave him.
博伊斯!
Boyce!
救我!博伊斯!
Help me! Boyce!
你手上的火
The fire from your hands,
我根本没感觉
I didn't feel it.
压根没温度
There was no fire.
根本伤不了我们
It couldn't have hurt us.
但幻象够真就能唬住
But to them the illusion was real enough.
那你装什么痛苦?
Why do you suffer then?
老娘开挂是要掉血的
The powers I wield come at a price.
我听见那怪物跟你唠嗑
I heard the monster talking to you.
它认得我
Gray Alys: He knew me.
八百年前的老相识
A long time ago.
几个意思?
How?
这地方藏着大宝贝
There is a great treasure inside of this place.
屌炸天的力量
An immense power.
有个男人找上门
A man came to me.
贪得无厌的野心家
He was greedy, power hungry.
都这德行
They all are.
但老娘来者不拒,就帮了他
But I can refuse no one, so I helped him.
结果这破地方有毒
But this place is poison.
这地方把他和手下都变成了你们看到的怪物
It turned him and his men into what you saw.
他本不该向我求助
He shouldn't have asked me for help.
从来没人应该向我求助
No one should ever ask me for help.
我就该被世人遗忘
I should just be left alone.
现在你跟着我走
You're with me now.
西边有踪迹
There are tracks to the west.
他们离得很近
They are close.
领主驾崩了
The Overlord is dead,
但王后怀有身孕!
but the queen is with child!
新领主万岁!
All hail the new Overlord!
领主驾崩了!
The Overlord is dead!
新领主万岁
All hail the new Overlord.
王后万岁
And all hail the queen.
All hail the queen.
领主与王后万岁
Hail the Overlord and hail the queen.
多谢大主教
Thank you, Patriarch.
如今我们各得所需
Now we both have what we wanted.
您有了继承人 我得了他的权能
You have your heir and I have his power.
十六年后您的子嗣才能亲政
16 years until your child will be of age.
他的权柄
We couldn't ask for his authority
托付给贤明之人最合适不过
to be in better hands.
您过誉了
You are too kind.
若非大主教睿智建言与鼎力相助
I wouldn't have anything, Patriarch,
我岂能有今日成就
not without your wise advice and unfailing support.
- 愿这份情谊永存 - 您忠实的仆人
- I hope that will never change. - Your loyal servant.
至死不渝
Always.
现在王座上坐着个肮脏的婊子
A dirty whore sits upon the throne of the city.
简直是在亵渎世间所有美好与纯洁的事物
An affront to all that is good and pure.
我们时间不多了
Our time is running out.
她的力量与日俱增
Her power grows stronger by the day.
给我找出那个女巫 拿到她的供词
Find me the witch. Bring me her confession.
到时女巫和娼妇就一起绞死在城墙上
Then the witch and the whore will hang together.
但要快 听见没有?立刻去办!
But hurry. Do you hear me? Hurry!
明日就能抵达骷髅河
Tomorrow we'll reach Skull River.
- 他会在那里吗? - 萨尔多?
- Will he be there? - Sardor?
不知道 但愿别碰上
I don't know. I hope not.
我必须独自面对他
I need to face him alone.
那你会死
Then you will die.
总得有人要死的
One always has to die.
你简直疯了
This is madness.
你该走了
You should leave.
你已完成契约
You did what I paid you to do.
当初就不该接受你的提议
I never should have accepted your offer.
但你还是接了
But you did.
走吧 博伊斯
Leave, Boyce.
- 保住性命 - 不
- Save yourself. - No.
放弃吧 回头是岸
Forget this. Turn around.
恕难从命
I cannot.
为何?
Why?
因为我别无选择
Because I have no choice.
我这人天生带衰 谁沾谁倒霉
No one should ever ask me for help.
灰姐
Gray.
回来
Come back.
跟我走
With me.
还不明白吗博伊斯?
Don't you understand, Boyce?
我身上有诅咒
I'm cursed.
靠近我的人都会遭殃
No one should ever get close to me.
老子不在乎
I don't care.
大祭司在召唤信徒了
The Patriarch calling to the faithful.
咱们谋划多年的时刻终于到了
This is the moment we've been working for.
从小仰望这座城堡时
What we've been dreaming of since we were small,
就日思夜想的时刻
looking up at this place.
但他能轻易毁掉这一切
But he can take it all away from us.
我的亲卫现在人数占优
My Overwatch outnumber his men now.
但他依然是个威胁
But he is still dangerous.
愿意为我做任何事吗?
Would you do anything for me?
赴汤蹈火
Anything.
真是我的好战士
You are my good soldier.
怎么突然变哑巴了？
Gray Alys: You're quiet.
前面就是骷髅河
Skull River lies up ahead.
追兵来了
They're coming.
甩不掉他们
We can't outrun 'em.
用不着甩
We won't have to.
- 女巫在这!- 对!
- The witch! - Yes!
属于咱们的时代终于来啦！
Our time is upon us.
动作快!没听见吗?
Make haste! Do you hear me?
赶紧的!
Make haste!
这次你插翅难逃!
You will not escape us this time!
这座城要改朝换代了
There will be a new day in the city.
妖女受死!
Repent, witch!
不!
No!
没了女巫助力
Without the witch,
咱们只能武力夺权
we must take the throne by force.
召集我的禁卫军
Assemble my guard.
都聋了吗?
Do you hear me?
弟兄们!弟兄们集合!
Brothers! Brothers, to me!
省省吧 你的弟兄都死绝了
There is no use. Your brothers are dead.
你这叛教狗贼
You heretic.
以山底城守护者
In the name of the Overlord,
领主之名
protector of the City Under The Mountain,
本座宣判你 大祭司 死刑
I hereby sentence you, Patriarch, to death.
老天爷 他到底杀了多少人?
Gray Alys: My God. How many has he killed?
所有反对者都被他屠尽了
Everyone that's come against him.
看看这些痕迹
Look at all this.
这里有人住
Someone lives here.
是萨尔多
Sardor.
这篝火几周没生过了
This fire hasn't been lit in weeks.
今晚月圆
Tonight will be the full moon.
月圆之时他就会现身
He will come then.
现在回头还来得及
It's not too late to turn back.
我们现在就能走
We could leave now.
你以为他会放我们走?
You think he would let us?
你猜他是不是正在监视我们?
Do you think he's not watching us?
你可以先走 我来拖住他
You could go. I could hold him back.
不
No.
已经太迟了
It is too late for that.
今晚就是满月
It will be a full moon tonight.
你还在惦记那个女巫
You're still thinking about that witch.
她向我保证过
She promised me.
你不需要她的承诺
You don't need what she promised.
你现在已经拥有一切了
You have everything now.
并非全部
Not everything.
银器?
Silver?
银器
Silver.
你们的武器毫无用处
Your weapons will be useless.
他们用银器对抗过他
They've come against him with silver.
银剑 银匕首
Silver swords, silver knives,
镀银的箭矢
arrows tipped with silver.
现在都化作了尘埃
They're all dust now,
那些英勇的镀银战士
all those brave, silvered warriors.
求你了 别这么做
Please, don't do this.
我们别无选择
We have no choice.
我感觉他越来越近了 博伊斯
I think he's very close now, Boyce.
你怎么看?
What say you?
还不到时候 还有时间 格雷
Not yet. There's still time, Gray.
猎魔人 你在撒谎!
I think you lie, hunter!
根本没有什么萨尔多
There was never any Sardor.
只有你
Only you.
你早就知道?你知道我的真身?
You knew? You knew what I was?
我曾真心待你
I cared for you.
这么久以来你都在欺骗我
All this time, you tried to deceive me.
你以为带我来这里
You thought you could bring me here
就能像杀其他人那样杀我!
and kill me like the rest!
你本不该
You shouldn't have ever
踏足此地--灰艾丽斯
come here--here, Gray Alys.
我警告过你的
I tried to warn you.
呃啊!
Argh!
冷静
Calm.
趁着月亮还被遮蔽 你需要休息
You need to rest while the moon is still covered.
你拥有令我嫉妒的天赋
You have a gift I'd kill for.
无论是否满月 你都能随心变形
You change at will, full moon or not.
不 那只是幻象
No. It was just an illusion.
为了分散你的注意力 让你露出破绽
To distract you, to leave you vulnerable.
我们是同类 格雷
We're the same, Gray.
- 你还不明白吗?- 我明白
- Don't you see? - Yes.
天生一对
Two of a kind.
你依然虚弱
You are still weak.
睡吧
Sleep.
嗯?
Hmm?
给我松绑
Untie me.
我不明白
I don't understand.
为什么?你救了我
Why? You saved me.
你不会喜欢我的答案,博伊斯
You would not like my answer, Boyce.
是月亮作祟
It's the moon.
你怕我再次变身吗?
Are you afraid of what'll happen if I change again?
我不会伤害你,灰艾丽斯
I won't harm you, Gray Alys.
-现在别闹 -我从未畏惧过你,猎魔人
- Not now. - I do not fear you, Boyce.
我太了解你了
I know you too well.
这一路上我摸清了你的所有弱点
I learned all your weaknesses along the way.
甚至还给你新增了几个
I even added to them.
你在说什么鬼话?
What are you talking about?
真的很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
但当你遇见我时,命运就已注定
But your fate was sealed when you met me.
你说得对,博伊斯
You were right, Boyce.
银制武器确实不够看
Silver weapons were not enough.
你给我下毒了?
You poisoned me?
必须让银元素融入你的血液
I had to put silver in your blood.
你当初就该让我死透
Why didn't you just let me die?
因为死物毫无利用价值
Because dead things have no power.
喂,等等,等等!
Hey, wait, wait, wait!
你--你必须实现我的愿望
You--you have to grant my wish.
"来者不拒"可是你的原话
You can refuse no one. Those are your words.
-你想要什么,博伊斯? -我要你
- What do you wish for, Boyce? - I want you.
我要我们永远在一起
I want us to be together.
并肩狩猎,共同战斗
I want us to hunt together, to fight together.
终结这该死的孤独?
To find an end to all this loneliness?
是的,你也渴望如此,我知道
Yes, you want it, too, I know it.
我向来有求必应
I refuse no one.
但需要付出代价
But there is a price to be paid.
尽管开口,任何代价
Name it. Anything.
很好
Very well.
女巫回来了!
The witch is back!
是她!就是她!
Man 2: It's her! It's her!
-她回来了!-她回来了!那个女巫!
- She's back! - She's back! The witch!
绞不死的女巫!
The witch that will not hang!
都给我回去干活!
Get back to work!
绞不死的女巫!
The witch that will not hang!
-绞不死的女巫!-打倒领主!
- The witch that will not hang! - Down with the Overlord!
推翻圣教会!
Down with the Church!
打倒领主!
Down with the Overlord!
推翻圣教会!
Down with the Church!
打倒领主!推翻圣教会!
Down with the Overlord! Down with the Church!
打倒领主!
Down with the Overlord!
推翻圣教会!
Down with the Church!
拿着这个
Gray Alys: Take this.
让女王割破手指
Tell the queen to cut herself,
将鲜血滴在皮甲上再穿上
to drip her own blood onto the skin and wear it.
今夜月相即将圆满
Tonight will be the end of the lunar cycle.
她必须在午夜前完成仪式
She must do it before the end of the night.
届时力量将归她所有
Then the power will be hers.
狼皮?
Wolf skin?
在巢穴中被猎杀的变形者之皮
The skin of a shapeshifter killed in its lair.
很好 灰艾丽斯 你完成了女王的委托
Well, Gray Alys, you have done what she asked of you,
却辜负了我的信任
but you have failed me.
我付钱买的是结果
I did not pay you for success.
现在 把怀表还给我
Now, give me my timepiece back.
不 杰雷斯 这是我应得的
No, Jerais. I've earned it.
但我的要求并未达成
But I did not get what I asked for.
可你得到了想要的东西
But you got what you wanted.
- 什么东西? - 女王本人
- And what is that? - The queen herself.
有个男人 她孩子的父亲
There was a man, the father of her child.
你觊觎王座 却视他为绊脚石
You wanted her, but knew he stood in your way.
我帮你解决了这个麻烦
I have changed that.
那人是谁?
Who was this man?
叫什么名字?
What was his name?
他叫博伊斯
His name was Boyce.
不!
No!
她杀了博伊斯!
She killed Boyce!
不 求求你
No, please.
我们本不该如此
It could never have been.
你在胡说什么?
What are you talking about?
他是头野兽
He was a beast.
野兽?
Beast?
你对野兽又了解多少?
What do you know of it?
他腐蚀了你 你变了
He twisted you. You changed.
是你策划了这一切
You did this.
我只是做了该做的事 我在保护你
I did what I had to do. I protected you.
- 你背叛了我 - 不 不是的 我...
- You betrayed me. - No, no. I--
你派人杀了他 我孩子的父亲!
You had him killed. The father of my child!
啊!
Oh!
- 求求你 - 不!
- Please. - No!
我愿为你做任何事
I would do anything for you.
那就为我去死
Then die for me.
我做这些全是为了你 博伊斯
I did this for you, Boyce.
为了我们能长相厮守 并肩狩猎
So we could be together, hunt together.
绞不死的女巫!
The witch that will not hang!
打倒领主!
Down with the Overlord!
怎么样 我的故事精彩吗?
So, how'd you like my story?
结局还没想好呢
I still don't know how it ends.
或许该让你尝尝活剥的滋味
Maybe with me skinning you alive,
就像你当初剥我的皮那样
just like you did to me.
这个结局我可不太喜欢
I'm not sure I like that ending.
可惜啊
Too bad.
我早知道你是女王的姘头
I knew you were the queen's lover.
- 别急着走嘛 - 你清楚我的底细
- Don't leave yet. - You know what I am.
- 我不能留在这 - 你说过唯一能让你
- I can't stay here. - You said the only woman
真心相爱的女人必须与你同类
you could truly love would be someone like you.
- 你不是那种人 - 若我能变成呢?
- You are not that. - But what if I could be?
我要你赐我化身为兽的力量,灰艾丽斯
I want from you the power to become a beast, Gray Alys.
- 我从不拒绝任何人 - 我要你辜负她
- I refuse no one. - I want you to fail her.
- 我从不拒绝任何人 - 我要的是你
- I refuse no one. - I want you.
我从不拒绝任何人
I refuse no one.
我早预见女王的欲望
Gray Alys: I knew that the queen's desires
终将引发革命
would lead to revolution.
她永远得不到你的皮毛
And that she would never wear your skin.
我早知你会活着
I knew you would live.
你在撒谎
You're lying.
就像我早知道这把枪会卡壳
Just like I know that'll misfire.
世人都说只要找灰艾丽斯
They say you can buy anything you might desire
就能买到任何渴望之物...
from Gray Alys...
...但最好别这么做
...but it is better not to.
这不正是我们想要的吗?
And isn't this what we wished for?